Guide to the JoAnn Evansgardner and Gerald H.F. Gardner Papers, 1965-1991 AIS.2001.09
ULS Archives & Special Collections
- Research Topics/Subject Files, IX.
  - Ehrlich, Ruth, 1971 (Box 33, Folder 52)
  - Fair Labor Standards Act, 1970 (Box 33, Folder 53)
  - Families, 1970-1971 (Box 33, Folder 54)
  - Famous Women, 1970 (Box 33, Folder 55)
  - Federal and State Labor Laws (Box 34, Folder 1)
  - Feminism, International, 1971 (Box 34, Folder 2)
  - Feminist Studies, 1971 (Box 34, Folder 3)
  - Sonia Pressman Fuentes, 1977 (Box 34, Folder 5)
  - Fundraisers, 1969 (Box 34, Folder 6)
  - Gallop Polls, 1970 (Box 34, Folder 7)
  - Gas Employees Union, Local 666 (Box 34, Folder 8)
  - Gerald Gardner Correspondence, Northern Ireland, 1969 (Box 34, Folder 9)
  - Gerald Gardner Correspondence (Box 34, Folder 10)
  - Girl Scouts, 1970 (Box 34, Folder 11)
  - Government Executive Article, 1969 (Box 34, Folder 12)
  - Governor's Commission: Reports on the Status of Women, 1967-1969 (Box 34, Folder 13)
  - Green, Edith, August 9, 1970 (Box 34, Folder 14)
  - Green, Edith, House Bill Sec. 805, HR. 16098, 1970 (Box 34, Folder 15)
  - Correspondence, Greyhound, July 10, 1975 (Box 34, Folder 16)
  - Griffiths, Martha W. Congressional Record, Speeches on EEOC, 1966; 1970 (Box 34, Folder 17)
  - Help Wanted Ads and Sex Segregation, 1969-1971 (Box 34, Folder 18)
  - Henley, David, 1977 (Box 34, Folder 19)
  - Hernandez, Aileen, 1974-1976 (Box 34, Folder 20)
  - Herndon, Calvin C., Resume, 1970 (Box 34, Folder 21)
  - High School Women, Rights and Social Studies, Various Publications, 1970-1971 (Box 34, Folder 22)
  - History of Women's Lib in PA, 1971 (Box 34, Folder 23)
  - Holt, John (Box 34, Folder 24)
  - Home Rule, 1972 (Box 34, Folder 25)
  - Household Employment, 1969-1971 (Box 34, Folder 26)
  - Humor, Cartoons and Articles, 1970 (Box 34, Folder 27)
  - Images of Women, 1970-1972 (Box 34, Folder 28)
  - INSTAD, Pamphlets and Correspondence, 1971 (Box 34, Folder 29)
  - Intellectuals, Newspaper Articles, July 12, 1970 (Box 34, Folder 30)
  - Correspondence, International Institute of Women's Studies (Box 34, Folder 31)
  - IRVIS Report, 1977 (Box 34, Folder 32)
  - JoAnn Evansgardner Correspondence, 1970-1977 (Box 34, Folder 33)
  - JoAnn Gardner Newspaper Clippings, 1969 (Box 34, Folder 34)
  - Jobs, Advertisements, and Job Finding Techniques, 1971 (Box 34, Folder 35)
  - Keller, Helen, Biographical Article, 1971 (Box 34, Folder 36)
  - Labor Unions, Positions on Women, 1970-1971 (Box 34, Folder 37)
  - League of Women Voters, Pittsburgh Area, 1970-1972 (Box 34, Folder 38)
  - Legal Rights, General, Pamphlets, 1968 (Box 34, Folder 39)
  - Legal Rights, 1971 (Box 34, Folder 40)
  - Legal Rights, Marital and Family Law, 1970-1971 (Box 34, Folder 41)
  - Legal Rights, Wives, 1970-1971 (Box 34, Folder 42)
  - Lesbians and Society, 1971 (Box 34, Folder 43)
  - Letter, 1980 (Box 34, Folder 44)
  - Local Government and Housing, 1971 (Box 34, Folder 45)
  - Correspondence, Macy, John W., 1970 (Box 34, Folder 46)
  - Maggie Martin Materials, May-June, 1977 (Box 34, Folder 47)
  - Martin, Marietta Case, 1971 (Box 34, Folder 48)
  - Maternity Benefits, 1970 (Box 34, Folder 49)
  - Math Skills and Testing, 1968-1969 (Box 34, Folder 50)
  - Media and Women, 1969-11971 (Box 34, Folder 51)
  - Medicine, 1970-1971 (Box 34, Folder 52)
  - Memos, 1977 (Box 34, Folder 53)
  - Mental Health of Women, 1969-1971 (Box 34, Folder 54)
  - Military, 1971 (Box 34, Folder 55)
  - Misogynism, 1971 (Box 34, Folder 56)
  - Moynihan Report, 1966-1967 (Box 34, Folder 57)
  - AACP (Box 34, Folder 58)
  - National Women's Party, undated (Box 34, Folder 59)
  - New York Times Article, Women Strike for Equality, 1970 (Box 34, Folder 60)
  - Newspaper Article, 1972 (Box 34, Folder 61)
  - Miscellaneous News Clippings, 1970 (Box 34, Folder 62)
  - Newsclippings, 1981-1982 (Box 34, Folder 63)
  - Newspaper Clippings (Box 34, Folder 64)
  - Newspaper Articles, 1970 (Box 34, Folder 65)
  - Nursing and Medicine, 1970 (Box 34, Folder 66)
  - NWRD, Adequate Income Plan, 1970 (Box 34, Folder 67)
  - New University Conference, 1969 (Box 34, Folder 68)
  - Ohlbaum, Judy, Dissertation on Personality Characteristics of Women, 1969 (Box 34, Folder 69)
  - Ordinances, 1969 (Box 34, Folder 70)
  - Patterns of Feminist Action, 1970 (Box 35, Folder 1)
  - Pegged in Place, 1970 (Box 35, Folder 2)
  - Peace and Anti-War Movement, 1970-1971 (Box 35, Folder 3)
  - Pennsylvania Feminists, 1971 (Box 35, Folder 4)
  - Pennsylvania Programs for Women and Girl Offenders, 1974 (Box 35, Folder 5)
  - Pharmacists, Women, undated (Box 35, Folder 6)
  - Pittsburgh Association for the Advancement of Women (PAAW), course listings, undated (Box 35, Folder 7)
  - Poetry by Women, 1971 (Box 35, Folder 8)
  - Police Complaints, ACLU, 1969 (Box 35, Folder 9)
  - Policing and Women, 1972 (Box 35, Folder 10)
  - Politics, Women in, 1970-1972 (Box 35, Folder 11)
  - Population and Birth Control, 1969-1970 (Box 35, Folder 12)
  - Poverty, Articles and Pamphlets, 1967-1971 (Box 35, Folder 13)
  - President's Task Force on Women's Rights and Responsibilities, 1969-1970 (Box 35, Folder 14)
  - Pressman, Sonia, EEOC Lawyer, 1969 (Box 35, Folder 15)
  - Problems of American Society Press, Washington Square Press, 1969 (Box 35, Folder 16)
  - Profession Status Reports, 1970 (Box 35, Folder 17)
  - Publications, 1977 (Box 35, Folder 18)
  - Miscellaneous Publications, 1971-1972 (Box 35, Folder 19)
  - Public Welfare Studies, 1973 (Box 35, Folder 20)
  - Publications (Box 35, Folder 21-23)
  - Publishing, Women and Professions, 1971 (Box 35, Folder 24)
  - Racism Research (Box 35, Folder 25)
  - Radical Women's Literature Conference, undated (Box 35, Folder 26)
  - Radical Women Seattle Washington, 1971 (Box 35, Folder 27)
  - Rankin, Jeanette, 1968-1969 (Box 35, Folder 28)
  - Rape, NYC Radical Feminists Conference, 1971 (Box 35, Folder 29)
  - Ravings, Anti-Feminist, 1970-1971 (Box 35, Folder 30)
  - Red Stockings Literature, 1969 (Box 35, Folder 31)
  - Religion; Articles, Clippings, Pamphlets, Correspondence, 1968-1971 (Box 35, Folder 32)
  - Sex Discrimination, 1972-1975 (Box 35, Folder 33)
  - Sexism in Language, 1970 (Box 35, Folder 34)
  - Sexism Checklists (Box 35, Folder 35)
  - Jane Wells Schooley, 1984 (Box 35, Folder 36)
  - Science, Women in, undated (Box 35, Folder 37)
  - Secretary, undated (Box 35, Folder 38)
  - Self Defense, Women, 1970 (Box 35, Folder 39)
  - Seneca Falls Convention, Resolutions, 1959 (Box 35, Folder 40)
  - Seneca Falls Convention Packet, 1982 (Box 35, Folder 41)
  - Sex Bias, undated (Box 35, Folder 42)
  - Sex Differences, Articles and Clippings, 1968-1972 (Box 35, Folder 43)
  - Sex Education, Clippings and Conference Bulletins, 1969-1970 (Box 35, Folder 44)
  - Sex Role Stereotypes, 1969 (Box 35, Folder 45)
  - Sexism, 1970 (Box 35, Folder 46)
  - Sexuality, 1970-1971, Clippings (Box 35, Folder 47)
  - J.B. Schneewind, 1970 (Box 35, Folder 48)
  - Shaler Area School District Collective Bargaining Agreement, July 1, 1974 (Box 35, Folder 49)
  - Single Women, 1970 (Box 36, Folder 1)
  - Source Book Press, 1970 (Box 36, Folder 2)
  - South, 1970-1971 (Box 36, Folder 3)
  - Stanton, Elizabeth Cody, undated (Box 36, Folder 4)
  - Statistics, 1969-1972 (Box 36, Folder 05-06)
  - Allegheny County EEOC Stats, April 9, 1974 (Box 36, Folder 7)
  - Statistics, Virginia Slims Poll, 1972 (Box 36, Folder 8)
  - Status of Women in Librarianship, 1970 (Box 36, Folder 9)
  - Stone, Lucy, undated (Box 36, Folder 11)
  - Straws Editor's Report, 1970 (Box 36, Folder 12)
  - Tapes, Women's, 1971 (Box 36, Folder 13)
  - T.E.A.C.H.E.R.S. (Box 36, Folder 14)
  - Television, 1969 (Box 36, Folder 15)
  - Testing, National Conference, 1973 (Box 36, Folder 16)
  - Tests, Psychological and Educational, 1971 (Box 36, Folder 17)
  - Theater, 1971 (Box 36, Folder 18)
  - Toys, 1972 (Box 36, Folder 19)
  - Sojourner Truth (Box 36, Folder 20)
  - U.S. Department of HEW, Women in Higher Education, 1971 (Box 36, Folder 21)
  - Labor Department, 1971 (Box 36, Folder 22)
  - U.S. Labor Department, Labor Legislation, 1970 (Box 36, Folder 23)
  - Women's Articles, 1977 (Box 36, Folder 24)
  - Women and Professions, Lawyer (Box 36, Folder 25)
  - Women and Professions, Librarians (Box 36, Folder 26)
  - Women in Leadership, 1973 (Box 36, Folder 27)
  - Women's Heritage Series (Box 36, Folder 28)
  - Women's Journals (Box 36, Folder 29)
  - Women's Strike, August 36, 1970 (Box 36, Folder 30)
  - World Fellowship Center Summer Program, 1970 (Box 36, Folder 31)
  - Zero Population Growth, 1970-1971 (Box 36, Folder 32)
  - Evansgardner Council Race, 1972 (Box 36, Folder 33)
  - Evansgardner for Council, 1973 (Box 36, Folder 34)
  - Brochures, Evansgardner runs for Council, undated (Box 36, Folder 35)
  - Color Problems, 1969-1970 (Box 36, Folder 36)
  - U.S. Department of Labor, Marital and Family Characteristics of Workers, 1968-1969 (Box 36, Folder 37)
  - Exploding the Myth, 1966 (Box 36, Folder 38)
- Publications, X.
  Evansgardner and Gardner kept files of publications that they used as references throughout their involvement with women's issues. Along with Evansgardner's personal card catalog of publications, this series contains articles, pamphlets, magazines, and newsletters dealing with feminism and racism, 1968-1975.
  - Miscellaneous publications, 1968-1975 (Box 36, Folder 39)
  - Farrell, Warren T. "The Resocialization of Men's Attitudes Toward women's Role in Society" (Box 36, Folder 40)
  - Article- A Bright Woman is Caught in a Double Bird, Matina Horner, 1969 (Box 36, Folder 41)
  - Facts Concerning Women, 1969 (Box 36, Folder 42)
  - Pamphlet, Goodbye to All That (Box 36, Folder 43)
  - Washington Monthly, 1970 (Box 36, Folder 44)
  - Alumni Times, 1973 (Box 36, Folder 45)
  - Pamphlet, Free Joan Bird, 1970 (Box 36, Folder 46)
  - Pamphlet, What Everyone Should Know About Black Americans, 1970 (Box 36, Folder 47)
  - Magazine, The Hard Times, 1972 (Box 36, Folder 48)
  - Article- Your Business is Her Business, 1970 (Box 36, Folder 49)
  - University of Pittsburgh, Opportunities for women, 1970 (Box 36, Folder 50)
  - Magazine, The New Republic, 1970 (Box 36, Folder 51)
  - Newsletter, Link-up, 1970 (Box 36, Folder 52)
  - Newsletters, Westside Center News and LA Women's Center Newsletter, 1972 (Box 36, Folder 53)
  - Miscellaneous Flyers and Publications, 1970-1971 (Box 36, Folder 54)
  - Underutilization of Women Workers, 1971 (Box 36, Folder 55)
  - Article- Spotlight on top Career Workers for the US, 1970 (Box 36, Folder 56)
  - Pamphlet- Help Wanted…or is it?, 1968 (Box 36, Folder 57)
  - Article- Bringing the National Board Closer to Membership, undated (Box 36, Folder 58)
  - The Allegheny Feminist, 1977 (Box 36, Folder 59)
  - Analogy with Blacks, 1969 (Box 36, Folder 60)
  - Card Catalog of Feminist Books, 1972 (Box 37, Folder 1)
  - Pittsburgh East (Box 37, Folder 2)
  - The Pittsburgh News Sun (Box 37, Folder 3)
  - Pittsburgh Press, How They Voted, 1969 (Box 37, Folder 4)
  - Pittsburgh Catholic, 1969 (Box 37, Folder 5)
  - Peer Perspective, 1981 (Box 37, Folder 6)
  - The Status of Women Articles, 1978 (Box 37, Folder 7)
  - Civil Rights, 1967 (Box 37, Folder 8)
  - Wisconsin Women, Newsletter, 1973 (Box 37, Folder 9)
  - Do It NOW Correspondence (Box 37, Folder 10)
  - Pittsburgh Newsletter Correspondence (Box 37, Folder 11)
  - Pittsburgh NOW Newsletters, 1970 (Box 37, Folder 12)
  - NOW Newsletters, 1979 (Box 37, Folder 13)
  - PA NOW Newsletters, 1973 (Box 37, Folder 14)
  - Newsletters, 1978-1979 (Box 37, Folder 15)
- Oversized Posters, XI.
  This series includes two folders containing 60 political, feminist, pro-choice, campaign, and demonstration posters collected by Evansgardner and Gardner.
  - Oversize Posters (60 items) (Map-case 8, Drawer 14)